Okay, so in this video we're
going to be covering the
basic difference between
quality standards and regulations.
So what's the basic difference between
standards and regulations?
All right, so let's discuss this then.
Now the basic difference is, standards are
generally best practices, industry best
practices, where the regulations are
generally imposed by the government.
That's the basic difference.
But even with the regulations,
there's a couple of different types.
de facto and de jure, which I'll cover in
just a second.
So, standards and best practices,
right?
These are industry best practices,
or you may have company standards,
company best practices.
Right, so generally established by the
industry or the organization.
So as a very simple example, PMI
standards.
These would be PMI's best practices.
A company doesn't have to use those
standards.
They don't have to use them.
But these are, you know, PMI, they're.
have set these standards.
Okay, so it's, it's an industry standard
more than anything else.
Okay.
Now, regulations on the other hand is
imposed by the government, right,
or some kind of government agency.
And there are two types.
You've got something called the de facto
regulation and de jure regulations.
De facto regulations are ones that are
widely accepted, have been adopted, right?
Sometimes, a lot of times, a standard can
start off.
or rather a de facto regulation can start
off as a standard, as
an industry standard.
But then it becomes so widely accepted
that actually ends up becoming pretty much
a government regulation or a government de
facto regulation, such as, for example,
the QWERTY keyboard layout.
That's a very simple example.
At the beginning, when the typewriter came
out, it didn't start off with a QWERTY,
but eventually became a quick keyboard,
and then from there, you know,
governments adopted it, and now that's
become the de facto regulation.
That's a de facto standard.
A de jure regulation, though, is something
that is more mandated by law.
For example, Aski, right, that's a very
simple example of a Dejure regulation.
Aski, which stands for American Standard
Code for Information Interchange, right?
So Aski text, and so and so forth,
right?
That is a Dejure regulation.
So these are the basic difference then
between a standard and a regulation.
Just make sure you kind of know the
difference between the two, right?
Standard is company or industry,
regulation is by the government.
And then you've got the de facto under the
Dejure regulation.